## Sunil Manandhar

sunil@ibm.com | +1(757) 345-9788 | https://linkedin.com/in/sunil-manandhar | https://sunilmanandhar.com

### RESEARCH

I am a Security and Privacy Research Scientist at IBM T.J. Watson Research Center. I received my Ph.D. from William & Mary. My research interests include IoT security, privacy, software security, and NLP. I completed my B.Sc. in Computer Science and Information Technology from St. Xavier's College, Nepal.

### **EDUCATION**

**Ph.D. in Computer Science,** GPA 3.85 - **The College of William and Mary**, Williamsburg, VA Aug 2016 - Jul 2022

Advisor: Dr. Adwait Nadkarni

Relevant Coursework: Advanced System Security Engineering, Advanced Topics in System and Security, CyberSecurity Research Analysis, Computer & Network Security, Advanced Software Engineering, Ubiquitous and Mobile Computing, Analysis of Algorithms, Intro to Machine Learning

**BS** in Computer Science and IT, GPA: 79.5% - Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

Nov 2011 - Nov 2015

### **PUBLICATIONS**

**Sunil Manandhar**, Kapil Singh, Adwait Nadkarni, "Towards Automated Regulation Analysis for Effective Privacy Compliance" in NDSS Symposium 2024, [To Appear]

Prianka Mandal, **Sunil Manandhar**, Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, Denys Poshyvanyk, Adwait Nadkarni, "Helion: Enabling Natural Testing of Smart Homes" in ESEC/FSE 2023 Demonstrations, Accepted [PDF|Artifact|Demo]

X. Jin\*, **Sunil Manandhar**\*, Kaushal Kafle, Z. Lin, and Adwait Nadkarni, "Understanding IoT Security from a Market-Scale Perspective," in Proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Los Angeles, CA, USA, 2022. \*Co-first Authors., *Accepted*. [PDF|Artifact]

**Sunil Manandhar**, Kaushal Kafle, B. Andow, K. Singh, and **Adwait Nadkarni**, "Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified: A Study of Availability, Content, and Coverage" in *Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX)*, Boston, MA, USA, 2022. *Accepted*. [PDF [Artifact]

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. Security in Centralized Data Store-based Home Automation Platforms: A Systematic Analysis of Nest and Hue. *ACM Transactions on Cyber Physical Systems, special issue on Security and Privacy for Connected CPS (TCPS)* [PDF]

**Sunil Manandhar**, Kevin Moran, Kaushal Kafle, Ruhao Tang, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses. *To Appear in the Proceedings of the 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P)*, San Francisco, CA, USA, May 2020. [PDF|CODE]

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. A Study of Data Store-based Home Automation. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. *Best Paper Award.* [*Press Coverage*] [PDF]

Sigmund Albert Gorski III, Ben Andow, Adwait Nadkarni, **Sunil Manandhar**, William Enck, Eric Bodden, and Alexandre Bartel. ACMiner: Extraction and Analysis of Authorization Checks in Android's Middleware. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. [CVE-2019-9351, CVE-2019-9377, CVE-2019-9438] [PDF]

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Research Scientist, Security and Privacy, IBM Research  Zero Trust Security  Relian Applicate		August 2022-
	Policy Analysis	
COV	Mes Fellow, Center for Innovative Technology  Model statewide privacy policies for Smart Community Testbed (ongoing)  □ Systematic Literature Review on privacy challenges in Smart Circuit  □ Interaction with Testbed Technologist and State/County officials	
Co-o	op, IBM	Sep 2020 - Dec 2020
	Privacy Compliance Framework  Created pipeline for NLP tasks to automate information extraction from partial Trained Named-Entity-Recognition (NER) Model to extract data objects  Multi Label Classification using BERT	privacy regulation and privacy policy
Rese	earch Intern, IBM	Jun 2020 - Sep 2020
	Framework for Privacy Policy analysis  Worked on extraction of entities and relation to understand information f Analysis of Privacy Policy using existing tools and techniques	low in privacy policies
Lead	d Grad Student, SPL Lab	Jan 2020 - Jul 2022
<u> </u>	Conducted weekly student-run meetings and organized events to improve research s Managed lab website and logistics [Website] Mentored 4 students in research projects	kills
Resea	Pearch Assistant, CS Department, William & Mary Designed framework for Regulation Analysis Analyzed Privacy Policies to develop insights into data protection practices Designed framework for generating natural home automation scenarios to improve so Developed proof of concept exploits for vulnerabilities in access control enforcement	
Teacl	Ching Assistant, William & Mary Computational Problem Solving	Aug 2016 - May 2017
Tech:	anology Lead, Universal Language Learning, China Built a chatbot engine for kids to help with language learning.	Dec 2016 - Dec 2021
Mobi	bile App Developer, Moondrop, San Francisco Managed Mobile Application and Updated the App with Material Design <a href="https://tinyaput.com/https://tinyap&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jan 2016 - Aug 2016&lt;br&gt;yurl.com/y65eafd6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Softv&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;ware Engineer, Bajra Technologies, Kathmandu, Nepal SiteHawk - Crawler, and Interface for WebsiteSite Deface Detection Imperial - Cordova based Mobile App for Side-Kick Plus Device&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jan 2015 - Jan 2016&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Busin&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;ness Associate, Axon System, Kathmandu, Nepal&lt;br&gt;MyFarm - Mobile Application&lt;br&gt;Driving License Mobile App &lt;a href=" https:="" s6rjgmo"="" tinyurl.com="">https://tinyurl.com/s6rjgmo</a>	May 2014 - Dec 2014

# **AWARDS AND HONORS**

	<u>International Student Achievement Award</u> - Reves Center, 2022		
	NSF CPS-Cyber-Physical Systems Grant		
	☐ Title: "Enabling Data-Driven Security and Safety Analyses for Cyber-Physical Systems"		
	PI: Adwait Nadkarni, Kevin Moran, Co-Pi: Denys Poshyvanyk, Contributor: Sunil Manandhar		
	□ Award CNS-2132281, totaling \$799,839		
	COVA CCI Cyber Security Dissertation Fellowship		
_	□ Title: "Improving Privacy, Security, Safety in Emerging Platforms"		
	PI: Adwait Nadkarni, Graduate Fellowship: Sunil Manandhar		
	□ Award Grant: 759381, totaling \$25,000		
	The Commonwealth of Virginia Engineering & Science (COVES) Fellow, 2021		
	S. Laurie Sanderson Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Mentoring Award, 2021		
	<u>Distinguished Reviewer</u> - Shadow PC, IEEE S&P 2021		
	Best Paper Award at CODASPY, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019		
	Received 3 CVEs and mentions on the Android Security Bulletin		
	Winner of Imagine Cup Nepal 2014		
	Winner of Skype Challenge in Imagine Cup 2014		
	President of Computer Science and Information Technology Association of Nepal (2014)		
	Microsoft Student Partner - St. Xavier's College (2014)		
	PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED TALKS		
٥	Enabling Natural Testing of Smart Homes		
	<ul> <li>ESEC/FSE 2023 Demonstrations</li> </ul>		
	Understanding IoT Security from a Market-Scale Perspective		
	<ul> <li>29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)</li> </ul>		
	Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified: A Study of Availability, Content, and Coverage		
	□ 31st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy		
	Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses"		
	□ 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy		
	□ IBM		
	☐ Journal Club, William & Mary		
	"Outlier Detection in Large Scale Dataset"		
_	<del>-</del>		
	□ 17th Annual Graduate Research Symposium		
	PROFESSIONAL SERVICE		
	Reviewer for IEEE S&P'24		
	Reviewer for PoPETS'24		
	Reviewer for PoPETS'23		
	Reviewer for ACM Wisec'21		
	Reviewer for ACM WiSec '21 Replicability Evaluation Committee		
	Reviewer for ACSAC Artifact Evaluation Committee		
_	Shadow PC for IEEE S&P '21		
0	Sub-reviewer for Conferences		
_	USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX) '19, '21		
	TIGET TYPE G. O. I		
	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·		
	□ ISOC Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), '20,'22		
_	The International Conference on Information Systems Security (ICISS), '19		
	Student Technology Advisory Committee (Arts and Science Department - William & Mary) ('20)		